aspworldtour.com 2018-12-20

# Privacy Policy - World Surf League

**Updated and Effective From: May 25, 2018**

Association of Surfing Professionals LLC d/b/a World Surf League and its related companies (referred to in this policy as “WSL”, “we”, “our” or “us”), support the protection of your rights to privacy as a fundamental element of its governance of professional surfing worldwide and the relationship it has with its members. This Privacy Policy sets out what data WSL collects from you, including through its online and mobile sites and applications (each a “WSL Digital Site” and collectively the “WSL Digital Sites”) and about you from any sources (for example at an event or from WSL sponsors or other third parties), how it is managed, shared or used. It also explains your rights in respect of your personal data. WSL pledges to conduct business according to this policy which applies to all Personal Data collected by WSL.

**If you have agreed to receive communications from us, but you later change your mind, you can revise your preferences on the "profile" section of your account, by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link within the e-mail you receive or you can email us at support@worldsurfleague.com.**

### 1\. Access by Children

The WSL Digital Sites do not knowingly solicit, obtain, retain or use any personally identifiable information or personal data from children under the age of 13 years. Accordingly, children under the age of 13 may be restricted from participating in certain features on the WSL Digital Assets. If WSL is made aware that we have collected Personal Data (as defined below) from a child under 13 years of age in a manner that is inconsistent with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, WSL will delete this information as soon as possible. For more details on WSL’s policy with respect to children, please see our terms and conditions of use accessible at <http://www.worldsurfleague.com/pages/terms-of-use>.

### 2\. Personal Data and other information

#### a. Information collected from you

Personal information or personal data is information about you that identifies you or information by which your identity or information about you can be reasonably determined (“Personal Data”). If WSL requires Personal Data, it is generally collected directly from you during the course of WSL’s relationship with you, and may be provided by you in correspondence (e.g. letter, form, email); through a WSL Digital Site when you register as a member to receive notifications, or to play Fantasy Surfing; by entering competitions, events, promotions, applications, gaming portals or membership application; or by your giving WSL such information in person. Generally, the type of Personal Data WSL collects directly about you, and which it may use as set out in this Privacy Policy, may include:

  * Your full name;
  * Your sex;
  * Mailing address;
  * Telephone number;
  * Interests;
  * E-mail address;
  * Age;
  * Nationality;
  * Financial Information such as credit card or bank details;
  * Next of Kin;
  * Geo location information;
  * Unique identifiers such as a user name or password;
  * Communication preferences;
  * Search queries;
  * Comments and other information posted onto an interactive online forum; and
  * Any other information otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.

#### b. Information collected automatically when you visit a WSL Digital Site

WSL may also collect certain other information automatically when you visit a WSL Digital Site including:

  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address which can sometimes also be used to get your general geographic area;
  * Other unique identifiers such as mobile device identification numbers, domain name of your internet or wireless service provider and type of device used to access a WSL Digital Site;
  * Browser type and settings and operating system used;
  * Webpages you visit within the WSL Digital Sites or sites you visited before or after you visit the WSL Digital Sites;
  * Information collected through cookies, web beacons, pixels, Local Shared Objects and other technologies; and
  * Standard server log information.

#### c. Geo-location information

By accessing the WSL Digital Sites from a mobile phone or through a mobile application, you may be asked to share your precise (GPS level) geo-location information with us so that we can customize your experience on the WSL Digital Sites, or on other sites when we work with a third party mobile ad platform. In most cases, you are able to turn off data collection through your mobile device at any time through the privacy settings on your mobile phone or through the settings in the applicable mobile application.

#### d. Cookies and Tagging Technology

In common with other website operators, we use standard technology called “cookies” on the WSL Digital Sites, in order to personalize your experience, administer the WSL Digital Sites, analyze trends and user data and gather demographic information. For further details on how we use cookies, and your choices regarding cookies, please refer to the WSL Cookie Policy which you can read here.

### 3\. Use of Information collected

WSL will only use information that it collects for the following purposes or as required by law:

  * to provide you with information about WSL events, promotions, functions, products or entries;
  * to notify you regarding WSL event or membership issues;
  * to be able to respond to questions or comments you have;
  * to contact you via email and otherwise about your account on a WSL Digital Site;
  * to inform you about products, services and events that may be of interest to you;
  * to customize and personalize your use of the WSL Digital Sites;
  * to enable you to enter contests or events that WSL promotes or conducts;
  * to pay you prize money or other applicable payments;
  * to assist in administration matters relating to events you may participate in;
  * to administer all WSL events and tours efficiently;
  * to contact you for discipline purposes as stipulated in the WSL rulebook;
  * to contact you urgently for any reason deemed necessary;
  * to market WSL events, sponsors, promotions and functions and to send you promotional materials or special offers on our behalf or on behalf of our sponsors or marketing partners and their subsidiaries and affiliates, but only where you have consented to receiving such emails;
  * to publish stories, comments, photos or other information posted in any interactive online section of a WSL Digital Site;
  * to use information collected through the WSL Digital Sites to evaluate your suitability to participate in surveys or focus groups for the WSL or a sponsor or partner of the WSL and to invite you to participate in any such survey or focus group;
  * to research, assess performance and analyze WSL marketing or advertising campaigns on the WSL Digital Sites or otherwise use analysis tools such as but not limited to Google Analytics; or
  * in accordance with the United States Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Principles, we may share your data with advertising networks and/or social media platforms for the purposes of selecting and serving relevant adverts to you via those networks/platforms, and to search engine and analytics providers. 

### 4\. Sharing of Information

  * Each WSL Entity may disclose Personal Data to other WSL Entities, which will use and disclose the information only for the purpose for which it was originally collected and as described herein. All WSL Entities abide by this Privacy Policy.

  * In some circumstances, WSL collects Personal Data about you from a third-party source (e.g. if WSL runs a competition or event in conjunction with a third-party co-promoter and you provide your Personal Data to it). As a general rule WSL will attempt to ensure any third parties from whom it obtains Personal Data about you comply with the privacy law requirements of your jurisdiction and have advised you that your Personal Data may or will be passed on to WSL and/or WSL affiliates or sponsors and that such third party has taken reasonable steps to ensure that you are aware of the purposes for which WSL is collecting your Personal Data and that you have consented to the same, including its use in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

  * WSL may engage third-party contractors to perform services which may involve the contractor handling your Personal Data. In these situations, WSL restricts such third party to using any of your Personal Data for the purpose permitted under this Privacy Policy.

  * When you register on a WSL Digital Site, we collect Personal Data which we use in compliance with your notification preferences, which you may alter at any time. We use a third-party provider, MailChimp, to deliver our e-mail notifications. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our e-mails. For more information, please see [MailChimp’s privacy notice](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). You can unsubscribe from receiving e-mails by changing your preferences in the profile section or by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our emails.

  * In limited circumstances WSL may provide your Personal Data to third parties such as co-sponsors or promoters of WSL events for use as permitted in this Privacy Policy. WSL may also share information about your use of the WSL Digital Sites in anonymized, aggregate form with our trusted social media, advertising and analytic partners for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, for example, to improve and personalize your experience on the WSL Digital Sites or to perform analytics.

  * Third parties such as WSL’s advertisers, sponsors, service providers or social media platforms, including, but not limited to, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and YouTube may receive or gather information about end users, including through the use of cookies, pixels, SDKs, web beacons or other tracking software and use that information for targeted advertising. WSL also uses third-party advertising companies to serve ads on WSL Digital Sites, which may, directly or indirectly, collect or use information about your visits to websites to display advertisements more tailored to your interests. 

  * Please note that while the WSL is careful about choosing its sponsors, advertisers and partner third parties, it is only responsible for the content on the WSL Digital Sites and for the use of your Personal Data by any WSL Entity. All third parties associated with a WSL Digital Site with whom WSL may share Personal Data are bound by their own privacy and data collection and protection practices. WSL cannot be held liable for the policies or actions of such third parties. We encourage users to read the privacy policy of any click-thru site they visit through a WSL Digital Site.

### 5\. Accuracy, Completeness and Deletion requests

  * WSL will take commercially reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Data is kept accurate, complete, and up-to-date. If any of the Personal Data WSL holds about you is inaccurate, incomplete or out-of-date, please contact WSL immediately using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy.

  * WSL shall recognize any valid requests from individuals to delete their Personal Data from use for any reason and has systems and procedures in place to comply with a request for deletion. Any such requests should be made by contacting WSL directly using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy.

### 6\. Other people's information which you provide to WSL

If you provide Personal Data to WSL about someone else, such as your agent or next of kin, you must ensure that you are entitled to disclose such information to WSL and that WSL can collect, use and disclose such information for the purposes described above without being required to do anything else under relevant privacy laws (which may include laws of a country they are from or in which they reside). You should take reasonable steps to ensure the individual concerned is aware of the contents of this Privacy Policy as those matters relate to them. You warrant that any information you disclose is true and correct.

### 7\. Security and Retention of your Personal Data

  * Personal Data the WSL holds is stored either in hard copy documents or as electronic data. WSL uses generally accepted industry standard reasonable security measures to protect any Personal Data held in any form from misuse, loss, unauthorized access, modification and/or disclosure.

  * Your membership on a WSL Digital Site is password protected and we recommend that you do not divulge your passwords to anyone. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your member name, password and other account information.

  * Any information posted or disclosed on a message board or comment section may be viewed and used by other members of the public. If you post any Personal Data in a publicly accessible area of a WSL Digital Site, you do so at your own risk and WSL accepts no liability for the same. 

  * WSL shall retain your Personal Data only so long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this policy, for as long as your account or membership is active. We respect requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws. We reserve the right to keep certain information in our archives that we deem necessary to comply with any legal obligations we may have, resolve disputes and enforce contractual agreements.

### 8\. Online and Mobile Advertising: Opting Out

  * If you wish to know more about interest based advertising, would like to know more about your options or would like to opt-out, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) web-site: www.networkadertising.org. NAI is a co-operative of online advertising companies who are committed to responsible practices and consumer protection. You may also visit the Digital Advertising Alliance website, <https://www.aboutads.info/choices> for more information about what you can do if you do not want to receive internet-based advertising.

  * European users can opt out from interest based advertising through the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance website at <https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>; and users in Canada can opt-out using the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada site at www.youradchoices.ca.

  * Facebook is an advertising partner and may collect and use data to display advertisements on all WSL Digital Sites. For more information and to control the ads you see, visit <https://m.facebook.com/ads/audience_network>.

  * Other analytic services such as Google Analytics provide services which analyze information regarding visits to our websites and mobile applications. They use cookies, web beacons and other tracking information to collect this information. To opt-out of analytics for the web, please visit the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on and install the add-on for your browser.

  * Browser and mobile operating systems also provide other privacy and ad-blocking mechanisms We encourage you to review the privacy control settings available in your browser or device platforms settings. Note that some of these controls (such as blocking third-party cookies) may affect the storage of your opt-out preferences. To express your privacy preferences or specific companies you may download and use an opt-out application such as DAA's AppChoices App at <http://youradchoices.com/appchoices>. 

  * You can stop all collection of information by the WSL App on your mobile device by uninstalling the WSL App. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. Most operating systems such as iOS for Apple phones, Android for Android devices and Windows for Microsoft devices also provide their own instructions on how to prevent delivery of tailored advertising to your mobile device. Please also review your mobile device’s privacy settings and support materials if you wish to opt-out of tailored advertisements. You can also request to opt-out via email to the contact address set out below.

### 9\. Social Networking

  * You may use certain third-party social networking services, including but not limited to Facebook, Google+, and others to share information about your experience on the WSL Digital Sites with your friends and followers on those social networking services. These social networking services may be able to collect information about you, including your activity on the WSL Digital Sites. These third-party social networking services also may notify your friends, both on the WSL Digital Sites and on the social networking services themselves, that you are a user of the WSL Digital Sites or about your use of the WSL Digital Sites, in accordance with applicable law and their own privacy policies. If you choose to access or make use of third-party social networking services, we may receive information about you that you have made available to those social networking services, including information about your contacts on those social networking services. Your interactions with those social networking services are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant service.

  * You also may be able to link an account from a social networking service (e.g., Facebook, Google+, Instagram) to your account on the WSL Digital Sites. This may allow you to use your credentials from the other site or service to sign in to certain features on the WSL Digital Sites. If you link your account from a third-party site or service, we may collect information from those third-party accounts, and any information that we collect will be governed by this Privacy Policy.

### 10\. Links to other Websites

The WSL Digital Sites may contain links to other websites or online services that are operated and maintained by third parties and that are not under WSL’s control or maintained by WSL. Such links do not constitute an endorsement by WSL of those other websites, the content displayed therein, or the persons or entities associated therewith. This Privacy Policy does not apply to those third- party websites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these third-party websites or services.

### 11\. Choice of Law

Any disputes that arise out of your use of the WSL Digital Sites shall be resolved according to the laws of the state of California, USA and shall be governed by the Terms of Use available here.

### 12\. Transfer and Storage of Data

  * While every effort is made to comply with the laws and regulations of all jurisdictions in which the WSL Digital Sites may be accessed please be advised that the WSL Digital Sites are directed towards users who reside in the United States. The servers on which data is stored, including any Personal Data, are located in the United States, and the WSL Digital Sites comply with relevant laws and regulations under Californian law, as explained in this Privacy Policy. By continuing to use the WSL Digital Sites you hereby consent to your information being collected, stored, and used in the United States, as stated in this Privacy Policy.

  * If you are located in the European Economic Area or the European Union or a country with data protection and/or privacy laws which are different from those in the state of California, please be advised that we may transfer your Personal Data to countries that may not guarantee the same level of protection for Personal Data as the one in which you reside. 

  * WSL will only transfer or share Personal Data to the extent it is necessary to fulfill the purpose outlined in this Privacy Policy and your data will be processed in accordance with the provisions set out in this Privacy Policy.

### 13\. California Privacy Rights

  * California law permits California residents to request certain information regarding the disclosure of their Personal Data to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to support@worldsurfleague.com or write to us at the address listed below.

  * Some web browsers transmit a ‘do not track’ signal or such similar signals to websites that a user may visit or interact with. At present, there is no recognized industry standard concerning what action, if any, a website provider must take with respect to such ‘do not track’ signals. As such, please be advised that, at present, the WSL Digital Sites do not take any action in response to such signals.

### 14\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 25, 2018, and will remain in effect except with respect to any changes in its provisions in the future, which will be in effect immediately after being posted on this page. WSL reserves the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time and we encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically. Your continued use of the WSL Digital Sites after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy on this page will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Policy. 

### 15\. How to Contact Us

If you need to contact WSL as directed in a section above or if you have an issue or question on this Privacy Policy, you can contact WSL at: 

Association of Surfing Professionals LLC dba World Surf League  
147 Bay St,  
Santa Monica, CA, 90405  
USA 

Phone: +1 310 450 1212  
Email: support@worldsurfleague.com  
Website: www.worldsurfleague.com
